(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-03T01:06:11.542174",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Bad sleep 不思議なステップで
Bad sleep, with a mysterious step,
踊り出すビート
a dancing beat.
今宵輝くネオンの下で光り
Tonight, glowing under the neon lights.
私可愛い可愛い魔女使い
I am a cute, cute witch master!
あの子はどこに ウダウダゴロゴロダラダラニャーニャー
Where is that child? Moaning and lazing around...
何も一言ない?
Not a single word?
甘い甘いチョコが食べたい
I want to eat sweet, sweet chocolate!
熱い熱いラテが飲みたい
I want to drink hot, hot latte!
穀物のパンが食べたいの? やだ!
You want to eat grain bread? No way!
ドロドロのチーズが食べたい
I want to eat gooey, gooey cheese!
フカフカのベッドで寝たい
I want to sleep in a fluffy, fluffy bed!
ウトウトおやすみなさい ルピー!
Dozing off, goodnight, Rupi!
わがままなんて言わないって
Saying I won't be selfish—
私賢いそうでしょう?
I'm smart, aren't I?
お願い Give give give するって 甘やかして
Please, give me give give, pamper me!
何もかも許される
Everything is forgiven.
だって私が1番可愛いんだから
Because I am the cutest one!
睡眠は木星において
Sleep takes place on Jupiter—
変わったビート
a changed beat,
今宵月明かりの下で
tonight under the moonlight.
誰をやる?
Who's next?
キャロチン呪術 容赦折伏
Carrot juice witchcraft, merciless subjugation,
お好きなオプションで
with your favorite options.
誰も私には敵わないいつわスマート
No one can rival me, playing it smart—
ニタイニタイ生が食べたい
I want to eat raw flesh!
紅い紅いスープが飲みたい
I want to drink red, red soup!
国々お肉が食べたいの? やだ!
You want to eat country meat? No way!
甘い甘いそれじゃ足りない
Sweet, sweet stuff isn't enough!
油断なフェイス また見せて
Show me that careless face again!
わがまま許されないわ
Selfishness is not forgiven!
わがままな私のこと愛してくれる
Will you love my selfish self?
誰かを待っているの?
Are you waiting for someone?
孤独な夜に一人ポツンとならして
Ringing out alone in a lonely night...
キミの推しはクローゼットの中でドッキリを仕掛けた
Your oshi is pulling a prank on you inside the closet
TRICK OR TREAT ほらもうキャンディーはない
Trick or treat, look, no more candy!
お腹がいっぱい？じゃあチェーンソーの出番かな？
Are you full? Time for a chainsaw then?
みんなが取り憑かれた その仮面を確かめよう
Everyone is possessed, let's check those masks
解剖しよう
and dissect them!
踊れ 隠れないで 泣き虫
Dance, don't hide, crybaby!
幻獣のないHALLOWEENは面白くない Haha
A Halloween without mythical beasts isn't fun, Haha.
みんなが照れている
Everyone is blushing...
かわいい
So cute!
熱くなった血をくれるでしょう？
Will you give me your warmed-up blood?
Myth or Treat ああ 呪いの配信
Myth or Treat, ah, a cursed stream!
ビビって叫んじゃえ！
Get scared and scream!
見せるよ今夜だけ まだ見ぬ恐ろしい顔を
I'll show you, tonight only, a terrifying face you've never seen.
なんてガチ恋NIGHT 魔女たちの出番だ
What a devoted-fan NIGHT, it's the witches' turn!
もう逃げられないよ 捧げて君の魂を
You can't run anymore, offer up your soul!
踊りだせTONIGHT 見て恐ろしいSIGHT
Dance tonight, behold a terrifying sight!
腹ぺこだ 食べたいな ねぇちょうだい？
I'm starving, I want to eat, hey, give me some?
曲れビビらせて 一緒に歌おう 嫁じゃなくてかぼちゃでDING-DONG?
Curve and scare them, let's sing together! Not a bride, but a pumpkin DING-DONG?
墓場で待ってる 覚悟できてる？ 我らの歌で盛り上がるがいい！
Waiting in the graveyard, are you prepared? Better get hyped by our song!
おびえて叫べ！
Fear and scream!
MYTHが暴れる これぞ我らのスタイル
MYTH runs wild, this is our style!
やった！楽しかった！
Yay! That was so fun!
いやすごくいい曲だったね！
Man, what a great song!
まさか歌えるなんてめちゃらうれしい
I never thought we'd get to sing it, I'm so happy.
ああ、今年も3Dで踊りたいよ！
Ah, I want to dance in 3D again this year!
え、みんな！
Eh, everyone!
いつになれるの？
When will that be?
わかんない！
Who knows!
わかんないけど楽しみにしててね
Who knows, but look forward to it!
確かに！画面がすごい！でかい！
True! The screen is amazing! Huge!
でかいね、あたしたち 巨人？
We're huge, aren't we? Giants?
このMyth or TreatはもともとENの皆で英語で歌った曲だったんだけど
This "Myth or Treat" was originally a song EN sang together in English,
日本語でまさか歌えるなんて思ってなかったです。嬉しい！
but I never thought we'd get to sing it in Japanese. I'm so happy!
え、メルもこの曲さ、聴いたときからめちゃ大好きな曲だったから
Mel, ever since I first heard this song, it's been one of my absolute favorites,
嬉しいよ！
so I'm so happy!
日本語版すごく自然に聴こえて歌いやすくてすごくあった
The Japanese version sounds so natural and easy to sing, it was great!
結構自分でね、これやったら可愛いかなっていうふうに直してみた
I adjusted it myself thinking, "Would this be cute?"
すごい！自分ね！
Amazing! You did!
メル様のこの誕生日に歌うっていうのもね、なかなかじゃないですか！
Singing it on Mel-sama's birthday is pretty special, isn't it?
おお、嬉しい！やばハロウィンだからさ、ぴったりだよね！
Oh, I'm so happy! Well, since it's Halloween, it fits so well!
いやもうメル様お誕生日おめでとう！お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday, Mel-sama! Happy Birthday!
ありがとー！やったー！
Thank you! Yay!
この後もあるんじゃないですか？
Isn't there more after this?
あ、そうなんだよ！まだ2曲目だからさ、まだまだ歌うんだけど…
Ah, that's right! It's only the second song! We're still going to sing more, but...
え なんか おばけ 感じ？
Um, like a ghost?
いや 今日はハロウィンだから まあおばけたちを おかし いっぱいもらいに行けないといけないんです！
Yeah, today is Halloween, so we can't go ghost-hunting, right?
えっ ちょっと待って、当たってるわ。
Wait, wait!
あーわかる！トリックオアトリート！
I know! Trick or treat!
食べに行っちゃう？食べに行っちゃう？
Trick or treat! Trick or treat!
ちょっと待って！めると行きたい！ねえ、ねえ！
Wait, wait! Mel wants to go too!
行こうってよ！
Let's go together!
ねえ！ずるい！やだ！先に行かないで！待って！
Hey, don't leave me behind! Wait!
待ってよ！待って！
Wait for me!
がんばってね！
Do your best, okay?
めい ちょっとよ。がんばってねって。
Mel, do your best, okay?
へえ 本当に寂しいじゃん……。
Geez, I'm so lonely...
あっ でも今日はね、Cubsのみんなが居るよね！
But today, all the Cubs are here, right?
よし！改めてみんな、コンカプー！
All right! Everyone, Con-Cub!
魔界の天才ヴァンパイア、夜空メルです！
It's Yozora Mel, the genius vampire of ghosts!
今日は最後まで楽しんでってください！
Today, please enjoy it until the very end!
そしてそして、ハッシュタグ夜空メル誕生2022でいっぱいツイートしてね！
And then, let's tweet a lot with the hashtag #YozoraMelBirthday2022!
写真もバシャバシャ撮ってください！
Take lots of photos too!
あとでメル見に行くからな。約束だよ！
I'm going to see Mel later, so it's a promise!
この後もまだまだコラボとかソロ曲とかたくさん続くので、ぜひぜひ最後まで楽しんでってください！
There will still be lots of collabs and solo tracks coming up, so please enjoy it until the very end!
よし、それじゃあこの後も一緒に楽しんでいくぞ！
Well then, let's enjoy the rest together!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
戦場へ！前線へ！そして死の淵まで！
To the battle! To the frontlines! To the brink of death!
命捨てたその覚悟を示せ！
Show them the firm resolve of those who will cast their lives away!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
聴こえるだろう あの砲声が
Oh can you hear the roar of the ringing cannon?
抵抗する蛆の声音だ
And down beneath it all, cries of struggling maggots.
踏み潰せ！踏み潰せ！
Crush them under foot! Crush them under foot!
諸君 我々の任務は何だ
Unit, I ask you: what is our mission?
殲滅だ！一機残らずの殲滅だ！
Annihilate all! Eliminate them all!
為すべきことは唯一つ 地獄を創れ！
We’re here for just one reason, to make hell on earth!
何故炎の中進んで行くのか
Why do we march through flame and fire?
弾丸の雨に打たれに行くのか
Do we march just to be gunned down?
笑止千万！帝国(くに)の為だ！
A foolish idea of the weak. We march for the fatherland!
戦場へ！前線へ！そして死の淵まで！
To the battle! To the frontlines! To the brink of death!
命捨てた覚悟を示せよ！
Show them the firm resolve of one who has cast away their life now.
忠誠を！従順を！そしてその魂を！
Your loyalty! Your servitude! Even your very soul!
全て捧げ勝鬨を上げよ！
Give them all up and cry out for our grand victory!
さあ此処に築いてみせろ！
Come let us build a tower into the sky!
天に届く死体(ひと)の山を！
A mountain of dead men, reaching the high heavens!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
どこに恐怖があると言うんだ
If you ask where fear lies, I will answer simply
見ろ 血肉が花火の様だ
Look right down here upon, the dazzling blood and bodies.
撒き散らす 撒き散らす
Scattered all around, scattered all around.
千の傷跡 忘れちゃいけないさ
I cannot forget my scars, a thousand drawn from years of war.
炎の熱も 零れた内臓も
The heat of fire, the burns it gave,
最後の呻きも 濁った瞳も
The final groans, the final breaths,
ああ それこそを求めるのだ！
Ah yes all of these memories! I’ll seek them out again!
安寧も平穏も増して和解なんて気の沙汰は
A tranquil peace, a world of love, reconciliation too?
牙を捨てた飼い犬の所業
They’re all barks of pet dogs who have cast aside their fangs – meek.
絶望と動乱を掛けた狂気の沙汰は
Despair and change, madness and rage, upheaval of the world
地獄よりも楽園の様だ
Such a heavenly place, compared to the hell the weak know.
その四肢は踊る為に
With those four limbs you were given by god,
踊り狂う為有るのだ！
Dance around our world in divine ecstasy!
人間に価値など無い 価値なき者同士の争いに
Humans have no true value, worthless beings fighting it out among themselves.
命の徒花を咲かせてみせろ！
Let the flowers of your lives bloom without fruit!
法律も秩序でも
Order and law are both forged by mad men,
狂った奴が創ってる
Even here chaos appears once again
まさに笑劇 不条理だけの起承転結
Now it’s all just a farce, an absurdity from the start, through the middle and end!
戦場へ！前線へ！そして死の淵まで！
To the battle! To the frontlines! To the brink of death!
命捨てた覚悟を示せよ！
Show them the firm resolve of one who has cast away their life now.
忠誠を！従順を！そしてその魂を！
Your loyalty! Your servitude! Even your very soul!
全て捧げ勝鬨を上げよ！
Give them all up and cry out for our grand victory!
さあ此処に築いてみせろ！
Come let us build a tower into the sky!
天に届く死体(ひと)の山を！
A mountain of dead men, reaching the high heavens!
木霊する憎しみさえ
Echoes of hatred, I cannot hear them now
掻き消す爆発音
They are drowned out by this song of guns!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
メル先輩 誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday, Mel-senpai!
ラプラスちゃん ありがとう！
Thank you, Laplace-chan!
なんかなんか、かっこよく決まったんじゃない？
Don't you think that looked pretty cool?
まあ、もともとかっこいいっすけどね（笑）
Well, I mean, I'm cool to begin with, haha.
こんなにさ、ちっちゃいのにびっくりしたよ、メル。
I was surprised by how tiny you are, Mel.
いや、ちっちゃい？ちっちゃいって何言ってんすか？
Huh, tiny? What are you talking about?
ほら！これ見て！
Look! Look at this!
角、角、角！ほらほら、これ！
Horns, horns, horns! Look, look, this!
ちょっと比べてみよっか。
Let's compare them.
まあ、いいですけど。
Well, if you want.
ほら、ね？
See? Right?
待ってよ、これ…ラプラスじゃん！
Wait, this is... it's Laplace!
メル、あ、ほら！メルの勝ちだね！
Mel, ah, look! Mel wins!
いや、メルの勝ち！いぇーい！
Yeah, Mel wins! Yay!
メル先輩さ、ラプラスちゃんちっちゃいの可愛いからいいんじゃない？
Mel-senpai, isn't it fine since Laplace-chan being tiny is cute?
いやいやいや、なんか丸め込もうとしてますよね？
No, no, no, you're trying to talk your way out of this, right?
あ、そうた。
Ah, that's right.
え、ちょっと話聞いてなくね？（笑）
Hey, you weren't listening at all, were you? Haha.
せっかくかっこいい歌歌ったんだしさ、二人でちょっとかっこいい決めポーズ、とらん？
Since we sang such a cool song, how about we strike a cool pose together?
おお、いいっすね！あ、それいいよ！えろえろ！
Oh, that sounds good! Ah, that's good! Lewd, lewd!
行くぞ人間たち！ばっちりスクショ撮るのだぞ！お、撮るのだぞ！
Here we go, humans! Make sure to take a solid screenshot! Oh, take it!
おっしゃ、あ、まず、あ、そうだな。片手を、て、手を、たにして、
Alright, first, ah, that's right. One hand, make your hand into a...
そうそうそうそう、突き出す感じ。
Yeah, yeah, like sticking it out.
おお、いいじゃないですか！必殺技みたいな。
Oh, isn't that nice? Like a special move.
はっ！わ、かっこよくない？
Ha! Wow, isn't that cool?
かつまっくせよ！かつまっくせよ！
Bow down before us! Bow down before us!
いいじゃん！
That's good!
あ、ラプメル…いいね、いいね。お次やろう？
Ah, Rapu-Mel... nice, nice. Shall we do the next one?
次、いいわ？
Next, okay?
じゃあ次は腕組みして、背中合わせで、
Then next, cross your arms, back to back,
お、いいね！うわ、少年漫画みたい！
Oh, nice! Wow, like a shonen manga!
いや、なんかめちゃくちゃちっちゃいみたい！あ、ちょっと…
No, it looks like you're super tiny! Ah, wait...
邪魔！角邪魔！メル角邪魔だって！メル写ってない！
In the way! Horns in the way! Mel, your horns are in the way! Mel's not in the frame!
メルさんちょっと服がエロいんで…かぶってるかぶってる！
Mel-senpai's outfit is a bit lewd... it's overlapping, overlapping!
また、またの、ヴァンパイアにならなようにね！
Also, make sure you don't become a vampire again!
え？気をつけないといけないっすよ。我が輩の気遣いね、これ。
Eh? You gotta be careful. That's my consideration for you, you know.
ほら。みて？
Look. See?
はあ？ドキドキしないから！
Huh? My heart isn't pounding or anything!
いや、なんでなんでなんで！
No, why, why, why!
こらこら！いや、いいから！邪魔！
Hey, hey! No, it's fine! In the way!
やめて！ドキドキ！おい！おい！
Stop it! Pounding! Hey! Hey!
こら！
Hey!
メルさん！ちょっと！
Mel-senpai! Hold on!
どうして みんなが幸せなの?
I wonder what makes everyone so happy?
この世界のこと 聞きたいって、知りたいって
Wanting to hear, wanting to know about this world
水辺の公園で みんなが耳を澄ませて
At the waterfront park, everyone strains their ears
わくわくするね ねぇ、オンディーヌ?
How exciting, right, Undine?
ハイハーイ!
Hi-hai!
さあさあ、みなさん 教えてあげまーす!
Now, now everyone, I'll teach you!
みんなが気になりすぎて困ってること、疑問に思いすぎて食事も飲まないこと ぜーんぶ丸ごと教えてあげまーす!
Everything you're too worried about, everything you're too doubtful about to even eat or drink, I'll teach you all of it!
えー、みなさんが幸福なのは…義務なんです。 幸せですか?義務ですよ?果たしてますか?
Um, everyone being happy is... an obligation. Are you happy? It's an obligation! Are you fulfilling it?
我々、幸福安心委員会っていうなの素晴らしい団体は、みなさまの願いを叶えたくはなくても、みなさまを支えまーす!
We, the wonderful organization called the Happiness and Peace of Mind Committee, won't necessarily grant your wishes, but we will support you!
幸福なのは義務なんです 幸福なのは義務なんです 幸福なのは義務なんです 幸せですか?義務ですよ?
Happiness is an obligation. Happiness is an obligation. Happiness is an obligation. Are you happy? It's an obligation!
ですから、安心して義務を果たすように! みなさまの幸せが 我々の幸せ 幸せですか?義務ですよ?果たしてますか? 幸せじゃないなら…
Therefore, rest assured and fulfill your obligation! Everyone's happiness is our happiness. Are you happy? It's an obligation! Are you fulfilling it? If you're not happy...
斬首 処刑 銃殺 釜茹で 溺死 電気 火 炙り 生埋め 薬殺 石打ち 鋸 はりつけ
Beheading, execution, firing squad, boiling, drowning, electrocution, burning, live burial, poisoning, stoning, sawing, crucifixion...
好きなのを選んでね♪
Choose your favorite♪
ハイハーイ!
Hi-hai!
さあさあ、みなさん 幸せだけが満ちてまーす!
Now, now everyone, only happiness is filling the air!
不安とか不満 なにかひとつないでしょ?
Anxiety or dissatisfaction, you don't have a single one, do you?
こわい!こわいよ? 幸せすぎて、こわいわ。
Scary! Isn't it scary? It's so happy, it's scary.
どうして みんなが幸せなの?
How is everyone so happy?
この世界のこと 聞きたいって、知りたいって
Wanting to hear about this world, wanting to know about it
水辺の公園で みんなが耳を澄ませて
At the waterside park, everyone is straining their ears
わくわくするね ねえ、オンディーヌ?
How exciting, right, Undine?
ハイハーイ!
Hi-hai!
さあさあ、みなさん教えてあげーるす!
Now, everyone, I'll teach you all about it!
みんなが気に気になってること 疑問に思ってること
The things everyone is curious about, the things they're wondering about
ぜーんぶ教えてあげーるす!
I'll teach you absolutely everything!
えー、みなさんが幸福なのは…義務なんです。
Um, everyone being happy is... an obligation.
幸福ですか? 義務ですよ?
Are you happy? It's an obligation, you know?
果たしてますか?
Have you fulfilled it?
ハイハーイ!
Hi-hai!
さあさあ、みなさん死にましたー!
Now, everyone, you have died!
オンディーヌをふった騎士は死にましたー!
The knight who rejected Undine has died!
葬儀に出るなら向こうに並べ!
If you're attending the funeral, line up over there!
それ以外は幸せに暮らせ!
Everyone else, live happily!
幸福なのは義務なんです。
Being happy is an obligation.
幸福ですか? 義務ですよ?
Are you happy? It's an obligation, you know?
幸福なのは義務なんです。
Being happy is an obligation.
幸福ですか? 義務ですよ。
Are you happy? It's an obligation, you know.
義務なんです。
It's an obligation.
義務ですよ?
It's an obligation, you know?
義務なんです。
It's an obligation.
幸福なのは義務なんです。
Being happy is an obligation.
義務なんです。
It's an obligation.
義務ですよ?
It's an obligation, you know?
義務なんです。
It's an obligation.
幸せじゃないなら 死ね
If you're not happy... Die.
一緒に怒られて 一緒に大きくなって
We were scolded together and grew up together,
一緒に涙して その分もっと笑った
We cried together and laughed more to make up for it.
仲良しの姉妹で 隠し事はないかった
We're siblings that get along, we've never hid anything from each other.
好きな人の話 いつか聞きたいかも
I'd like to hear about the person you like one day.
仲良しの姉妹で 隠し事はなかった
We're siblings that get along, we've never hid anything from each other.
好きな人の話 いつか聞きたいかも
I'd like to hear about the person you like one day.
突然どうしたの? うちら仲良しだけど
What's with the sudden question? We get along, but
大人になるほどね 秘密増やしていいの!
The more we grow up, you see, the more secrets we can keep!
予想は芸能関係 爽やかな王子様?
My guess is that it's a celebrity, maybe a handsome prince?
どうしよう…全然違うし だけどいいの 王子様
What do I do... she's completely off, but it's alright — he is a prince!
ぶりっ子して ほっぺつけて ポーズ決めて アップしよう
Acting cute, putting on blush, striking a pose, let's take a close-up!
大好きだよ 大好きだよ 見つめあって「可愛いね」って
I love you, I love you, turning to look at each other "We're cute, aren't we?"
苦手なこと 得意なこと 好みだとか それぞれじゃん?
The things we're bad at, good at, and like—they're different, right?
嫌いだよ 嫌いだよ 喧嘩しても ずっと一緒だよね
I hate you, I hate you, even if we fight, we'll always be together, right?
るるりら
(Ruru rira~)
こちらの方ですが お付き合いをしてます!
I'm going out with the person to my right!
イメージ真逆でも ちゃんと仲良くしてね
Even if he's the complete opposite, please try and get along with him.
取られたくないから 少し拗ねてみたけど
I didn't want you to be taken away, so I tried sulking a bit, but
ほんと楽しそうで 私も嬉しくなった
You seemed so happy, it made me happy too.
気になる人とかいないの? お姉ちゃんに教えて
Is there anyone you're interested in? You can tell your big sister.
決めたの 恋愛は禁止 今はダメ 夢のため
I've decided, dating is off-limits, not for now — for the sake of my dream!
キメ顔して 変顔して 泣き笑いも アップしよう
Making a serious or funny face, laughing or crying, let's take a close-up!
大好きだよ 大好きだよ 見つめあって 可愛いねって
I love you, I love you, turning to look at each other "We're cute, aren't we?"
似ているとか 似ていないとか 趣味だってさ それぞれじゃん?
"We're so alike," or "We're not the same," our interests—different, right?
嫌いだよ 嫌いだよ 仲直りも きっとすぐできる
I hate you, I hate you, we'll make up again, right away, won't we?
るるりら
(Ruru rira~)
一つ屋根の下で 明日も騒ごう
Living under the same roof, let's make a ruckus again tomorrow!
おーっす！みらいのチャンピオン
Hi, future champion!
今日も一日はりきっていきましょう
Let's do our best today as well!
ゲット！ゲット！（ゲット！ゲット！）
Catch! Catch! (Catch! Catch!)
さあ どんどん仲間をあつめちゃおう
Come on, let's gather up lots of friends!
スーパーボールでもハイパーボールでもマスターボールでも
Whether it's a Poké Ball, Great Ball, Ultra Ball, or Master Ball,
捕まえられないよ君のハート
I can't capture your heart!
でもいっしょに踊ればどんどん元気がわいてくる
But if we dance together, our energy will well up more and more!
ノーマル かくとう どく じめん ひこう むし いわ ゴースト
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost,
はがね ほのお みず でんき くさ こおり
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice,
エスパー ドラゴン あく フェアリー
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy!
進化前も進化系もみーんな集まってっでっでっでっで
Pre-evolutions, evolved forms, everyone gather round!
全力で！ポーズを！決めるんだ！
With all your might! Strike a pose!
メラメラボウボウ炎が燃え上がる
Blazing, roaring flames burn up!
ビリビリビリビリでんでんしびれてしまう
Zapping, crackling electricity makes you numb!
ヒュードロロンドンとゴーストがケケケのケ
Howling ghouls go "Ke-ke-ke-ke"!
世界一の格闘家ビシビシビシビシドーン！
The world's number one martial artist goes "Bishi-bishi-doon!"
出会えてよかった キミにきめてほんとうよかった
I'm so glad I met you, I'm so glad I chose you!
イェー！メル先輩、ハッピーバースデー！
Yay! Mel-senpai, happy birthday!
あー、めりあ、サンキュー！
Ah, Amelia, thank you!
一緒に歌って踊れて楽しかったよ！
It was so fun singing and dancing together!
あ、メルも！
Ah, me too!
あのね、今日はさ、メルの誕生日だから、何かご褒美ちょうだい！プリーズ！
You know, today is my birthday, so please give me a reward! Please!
え？
Eh?
何が？何がいいかな？うーん、じゃあプリーズキスミ？
What? What would be good? Hmm, then... please kiss me?
わお、メル先輩！
Wow, Mel-senpai!
うわ！大好き！私も！
Woah! I love you! Me too!
アイラブ、アメリア！うれしー！
I love Amelia! I'm so happy!
これからも一緒に遊んでください！
Please keep playing with me from now on too!
オブコース、アメリア！アイウォンテッドトゥサムシングウィズユー！
Of course, Amelia! I wanted to do something with you!
アメリアとやりたいことある？
Is there anything you want to do with Amelia?
あのね、サードフェスで踊ってたダンスが可愛かったから、一緒にやりたい！
You know, the dance you performed at the 3rd Fes was so cute!
いいよ！プルプル、プルプル！
Sure! Puru-puru, puru-puru!
せーの！プルプル…
Ready, go! Puru-puru...
ダンス可愛かったよ！
That dance was so cute!
エヴリワン、テイクロッツオブピクチャーズ、オッケー？
Everyone, take lots of pictures, okay?
いっぱい撮った？写真撮った？
Did you take a lot? Did you take pictures?
ちょっとアメリア、近くに…あ、ぎゅー！チーズ！
Hey Amelia, come closer... Ah, hug! Cheese!
ぎゅ、チーズ！うー、可愛い！キュート！キュート！ウィーアーキュート！
Hug, cheese! Ooh, cute! Cute! Cute! We are cute!
メル先輩、本当に可愛い、めちゃ可愛い！アメリアも可愛いよ！ありがとう！
Mel-senpai, you're really cute! Amelia is cute too!
ナイスシスター！おー、ナイスシスター！
Nice sister! Oh, nice sister!
また遊ぼうね！あー、メル先輩、これからもよろしくね！よろしくね！
Let's hang out again! Mel-senpai, please take care of me!
また遊ぼうね！これからもメルをよろしく！ばいばーい！
Let's play again! Please keep supporting Mel! Bye-bye!
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー
Dear Doppelganger
「どうもこんにちは 君の分身です」
"Hello and nice to meet you, I'm another you."
何の冗談か 目をこすってみる
Rubbing my eyes wondering if it's some kind of joke
影がふたつつき伸びて そしてまた幕は上がる
Two shadows stretch out, and once again the curtain rises
「もうひとり自分がいたらとあなたは言いました」
"You said, 'What if there was another me?'"
「そんな紳士な願いが僕を呼んだのさ」
"And such a gentlemanly wish is what called me forth"
過程はいいから結果を下してください 無意味で無意味な代償
Give me the results, I don't care about the process, a meaningless and pointless price
ねえこんなことより大事なことがあるんだよ いいだろう
Hey, there's something more important than this, isn't that fine?
「ええやりますやります何でもやります」
"Yes, I'll do it, I'll do it, I'll do anything"
僕は君の分身です
I am your alter ego
含み笑いでメサイアは言う
With a subtle smile, the Messiah says,
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は君は誰？
Dear Doppelganger, who, oh who are you?
ああ混濁と交差して僕は誰？
Ah, mixing and crossing in confusion, who am I?
ねえ有りもしない0と1
Hey, a nonexistent zero and one
証明の根拠なんて何処にも
There is no basis for proof anywhere
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰は誰は君？
Dear Doppelganger, who, oh who is you?
潜まられた存在に世界は気付かないね
The world doesn't notice a corrupted existence
鳴り止まない 目覚めない 奇跡の輪廻が
An endless ringing, an endless waking, the cycle of miracles
狂った正解を染め上げて
Dyes the distorted correct answer
ルンパッパ
Run-pappa
どうも様子がおかしい月曜日
Something feels strange about this Monday
ひとつふたつと崩れゆく辻褄が
One by one, the crumbling inconsistencies
僕を猜疑する 「お前は一体誰だ」と
Doubt me, saying, "Just who on earth are you?"
君は 君は 誰?
Who are you, who are you?
ちょっと待って
Wait a second,
知らない昨日 知らない言葉
unknown yesterday, unknown words.
そうやっていつの間にやら
That's how, before I knew it,
影は溶けゆく 僕はなんだろうね
shadows melt away. What am I?
ねえどうか存在を返して
Hey, please give me back my existence.
「生生様様がこっちはこっちはで、随分心地が良くて」
"My doppelganger has it so good over here,"
「もうあなたの居場所は此処にはない事分かってるんでしょ?」
"and you know your place has no right to be here, right?"
「ねえ奪われたなら奪えばいいだろ」
"Hey, if it was stolen, just steal it back,"
「今度は前のお前の番だから」
"since it's your turn now."
含み笑いで 侵略者インベーダーは嗤う
The invading invader sneers with a chuckle.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は君は誰?
Dear Doppelganger, who are you, who are you?
吶喊混濁と交差して僕は誰?
Whose voice am I, crossing with the turbid shouts?
命の椅子は一つだけ
There is only one chair for life.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰は誰は君?
Dear Doppelganger, who, who are you?
抉まれた存在に 世界は気付かないね
The world doesn't notice the hollowed existence.
零れ落ち了一粒 乾き果てる前に
Before a single spilled drop dries up completely,
誰でもいい 何でもいい 器を下さい
anyone, anything, please give me a vessel.
狂った正解が染め上げてロンパッパ
A distorted correct answer stains it all, ron-pappa!
Pray それはずつと続く ヒトの業の連鎖
Pray, it continues on forever, the chain of human karma.
Pain 委ねあって許し合って 満たされ往く
Pain, yielding to each other, forgiving each other, filling up.
Pray 欠けたピース無価値のペイン 渇望また愛も
Pray, missing pieces, worthless pain, yearning and also love.
Pain 託し合って生まれ変わる イニシエーション
Pain, entrusting to each other, a reborn initiation.
「僕の方がちゃんと君を生きてるからさ」
"Since I'm living your life properly,"
「君も次の誰かちゃんと救わなくちゃ」
"you have to properly save the next somebody, too."
「もう分かってんだろ 何をすればいいかさ」
"You already know what you need to do, right?"
「どうか誰か僕に奇跡をくれや」
"So someone, please, give me a miracle!"
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は君は誰?
Dear Doppelganger, who are you, who are you?
吶喊混濁と交差して僕は誰?
Whose voice am I, crossing with the turbid shouts?
もう止まらない 戻れない
There's no stopping, no going back now.
「どうもこんにちは 君の分身です」
"Hello there, I'm your doppelganger."
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー それはそれは僕
Dear Doppelganger, that is, that is me.
抉まれた存在に 世界は気付こうと
Though the world tries to notice the hollowed existence,
もう鳴り止まない 醒め止まない 奇跡の輪廻が
the unending, unsleeping reincarnation of miracles
狂った正解を染め上げてさ うまくやれよロンパッパ
stains the distorted correct answer—play it well, ron-pappa!
「どうもこんにちは 君の分身です」
"Hello there, I'm your doppelganger."
どうだっていい事を 嘘吐いて吐いて戻れない
Telling whatever lies I please, I can't go back.
時効なんてやってこない 奪ったように奪われて
Statute of limitations never comes, as I'm robbed just as I robbed.
今日だって叶わない 想ったように騙せない
Even today it doesn't come true, can't deceive the way I hoped.
腐っている僕には 腐っているものが理解(わか)らない
Rotten as I am, I can't understand rotten things.
おいでココまで 捨ていど
Come all the way here, throw it away—
「隠して仕舞い込んだんだ」
"I hid it and locked it away."
メーデー ぼくと分かっても
Mayday, even if you know it's me,
もう抱き締めなくていいんだよ
you don't have to hold me anymore.
ねえ メーデー ぼくが分かったら
Hey, Mayday, once you figure out it's me,
せめて笑ってくれるかな
will you at least smile for me?
(Say Woh...)
知っているのにね
Even though you know,
(Say Woh...)
僕らは人形
we are mere puppets.
そうやって今日だって飲み込んでいくんだろ 痛いくらいが愛しいよ
Swallowing it down today too—painful as it is, it's sweet.
「どうだっていい」なんて言うはずが
Saying "I don't care about anything"—
劣いて逝けよ そこにいるから
fade and rot away, since you're right there.
交際の秘訣は 魂(こころ)を売る事もう戻れない
The secret to association is selling your soul, and you can't go back.
綺麗事だって知るんだよ
I know it's just sugarcoating.
(Say Woh...)
本当だって知るんだよ
I know it's the real deal.
(Say Woh...)
空虚だって知るんだよ ねえ
I know it's all empty, hey.
臆病だって構わない 祈って置いてそれは無い
Cowardice is fine, but praying and leaving it behind? That's not right.
散々塞いだ情熱が ボケを掘っているとは 追い目…どこまで?
Passion blocked up all this time is digging its own grave—guilt... how far?
逃げ場を探して知るんだよ
I find out by searching for a place to run.
(Say Woh...)
期待の原則は
The principle of expectation—
騙したほうが正義なの
is that the one who deceives is in the right.
臆病だって構わない 祈って置いてそれは無い
Cowardice is fine, but praying and leaving it behind? That's not right.
散々塞いだ情熱が ボケを掘っているとは 追い目…どこまで?
Passion blocked up all this time is digging its own grave—guilt... how far?
被害者面したって「ねえ次こそは作ってよ」
Even if you play the victim: "Hey, make it right this time."
常識人ぶるのは夢みたいなら 精々絶滅をサバイブよ
If acting like a civilized person is a dream, survive extinction to the utmost.
最後まで甘え尽くしちゃうのは 暴力イラって知るんだよ
Pampering yourself all the way to the end—you realize it's violent irritation.
(Say Woh...)
真空だって知るんだよ
You realize it's a vacuum.
(Say Woh...)
足らないものを望んだら 僕じゃない僕を生み出す
If you yearn for what you lack, you give birth to a me that isn't me.
後悔の原則は 騙したほうが正義なの
The principle of regret is that the one who deceives is in the right.
被害者面したって「ねえ次こそは作ってよ」
Even if you play the victim: "Hey, make it right this time."
常識人ぶるのは夢みたいなら 精々絶滅をサバイブよ
If acting like a civilized person is a dream, survive extinction to the utmost.
最後まで甘え尽くしちゃうのは 暴力イラって知るんだよ
Pampering yourself all the way to the end—you realize it's violent irritation.
(Say Woh...)
真空だって知るんだよ ねえ
You realize it's a vacuum, hey.
暴れ出すって知るんだよ (Say Woh...)
I know it's starting to rage... (Say Woh...)
狂い出すって知るんだよ (Say Woh...)
I know it's starting to go mad... (Say Woh...)
空白だって知るんだよ ねえ
I know it's a blank space, hey.
ねえ
Hey.
どうだっていい言を
Whatever is fine,
嘘って吐いて戻れない
telling lies and unable to turn back.
飼い馴らせ僕を愛してよ
Tame me, and love me.
未だに僕を疑ってたの
Were you still doubting me?
君には僕が見えるかな
Can you see me,
孤独なピエロが
this lonely clown?
メーデー 僕と分かっても
Mayday! Even if you know it's me,
もう抱き締めなくていいんだよ
you don't need to hold me close.
メーデー 僕が解ったら
Mayday! If you figure out who I am,
もう一度笑ってくれるかな
will you smile for me once more?
メーデー 僕を叱ってよ
Mayday! Scold me,
正直者が夢みたいなら
if an honest person is like a dream.
ああ 幻が突き刺すんだよ
Ah, illusions pierce right through me.
そっと突っ立って死ぬんだよ
Standing still quietly, I die.
メーデー 僕を甘やかしてよ
Mayday! Pamper me,
もう磁器を割るこの世界から
from this world where porcelain breaks.
ああ 幻が突き刺すんだよ
Ah, illusions pierce right through me.
どうだっていいことを 嘘って吐いて戻れない
Whatever is fine, telling lies and unable to turn back.
事故なんてやってこない 奪われたように奪われて
Accidents never happen, taken away just like it was taken.
ああ、メル先輩！ お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Ah, Mel-senpai! Happy birthday!
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you so much!
いやー、ほんと、一緒に歌えて嬉しいです！メルさん嬉しい！
Man, I'm so glad we could sing together!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
なんですけど、ちょっと、こよみねる先輩にこの機会にちょっと聞きたいことがあるんですが。
But um, I have something I want to ask Mel-senpai.
なに？
What is it?
あの、なんか今宵とは、ワンナイトとかツーナイトとか、ちょっと前行ってたじゃないですか。
You were talking about "one-night" stands earlier, right?
ああ、ね、おっとね、そのこと。
Ah, right, oh my, about that.
そこんとこどうなんですか？結局今宵のことどう思ってるんですか？
What's the deal with that? How do you really feel?
え！？ ああ、いや、今宵、え、何言ってんだ。
Eh?! Ah, no, what are you talking about?
もう初めてのお風呂も、そのほかもろもろも、今宵が初めてなんだぜ。
Even my first bath was with Koyo, you know.
え、それってどういう意味か、わかるよな。
Eh, you know what that means, right?
ちょっと、急に、急に、え？
Wait, suddenly, eh?
だー！なんか、こう、聞こえた気がするけどな、今心の声が。
It felt like I heard a voice from the heart.
え、あ、そう、こゆちゃん、こゆちゃん、あ、そうだそうだ。せっかくさ、3Dコラボなんだから、一緒に、ね、写真撮ろうよ。
Since it's a 3D collab, let's take a picture!
あ、はい、あ、撮ります。なんか、流された気がするけど、まあいいや。
Ah, I'll take it. I feel brushed off, but oh well.
よし、じゃあ、え、撮りましょう。撮ろう、やった！ 撮ろう、やった！ え、じゃあ、何撮ろうかな、どうしましょうか。
Let's take a cool detective pose!
じゃあ、名探偵メルこよだから、我らね、なんかせっぽいポーズで撮らん？
Well, since we're Detective Mel-Koyo...
あ、いいですねー！そしたら、じゃあ、あれかな、
Ah, that sounds nice!
あれだね、あれだね、きっと。じゃあ、背中合わせにして、かっこよく決めよう。オッケーです！
Let's go back-to-back and strike a cool pose!
いくよ？ せーの、真実はいつもひとつ！ あ、かっこいい！ かっこいい！ 決まったんじゃない？ みんなバシャバシャ撮ってね。撮ってください！
Ready? One, the truth is always one! Cool!
いいね、いいね、これは謎が解けるぞ。これあのご名探偵の名も迷うじゃなくて、名前の何に謎になりそうですね。
Nice, this will solve the mystery!
そうだ、そうだな。じゃあ次は、え、ちょっと、はい。
That's right. Then next, yes.
あの、可愛い
Um, cute...
あの、ちょっとね、ちゃんとこよみとはもうワンナイトとか言わせないために、ちょっとぎゅって感じの、ちょっとぎゅって感じの、じゃああの証拠写真撮ってもらっていいですか？
So people don't talk about one-night stands anymore, can you take a photo of us hugging tightly?
なんか流された感じしたんでね。
I feel like I got brushed off again.
じゃ、い、いいですか？じゃ、ぎゅってして。はい、やったー！ぎゅー！
Alright, let's hug tightly. Yes, yay! Hug!
うわ、はずかし、はずかしい。やば、なんか、ドキドキして伝わってき気がする。
Embarrassing... I feel my heart beating through.
お風呂入ったけど、こういうのは初めてだよ。こよちゃん、あ、こよも、あ、は
This is a first for me, Koyo-chan.
取られている、みんなに。大勢に見られて取られている。
We're being watched and captured by a huge crowd.
ちょっと、それなんかちょっと、あの、なんかちょっと、ええなんなんだ。
Wait, what is this supposed to mean?
何考えてんのもう。ううん、なんでもない、なんでもないです。
What are you thinking? It's nothing!
こよちゃんだって今日は本当にありがとう。一緒に歌えてめるもめっちゃくちゃ嬉しかったよ。
Mel was so happy to sing together today!
こよの方こそです！これからも、ラブラブしていきましょうね！
It's the other way around! Let's keep being lovey-dovey!
しっていこーね！やった！こんこよー！こんこよー！こんこんこんこよー！
Let's do that! Yay! Konkoyo!
ぽっとしたり ぐっとしたり (萌えちゃう)
Blushing, getting exciting (moe),
はっとしたり ドキドキ (の♥)
getting startled, my heart races!
魅惑を隠す箱 秘宝に香る危なげな
A box hiding allure, the dangerous scent of hidden treasure
dangerous marine smell
❤️ ahoy ❤️
(これ開けたら君たちになんて言ってあげとくべきかな…？)
(What should I say to you guys when I open this...?)
「探してたのはせ・ん・ち・ょ・お？」うーん…
"Were you looking for Ca・pt・ai・n?" Hmm...
「あぁん❤️そんなにがっついちゃダメだぞ❤️」かな？
"Ah ❤️ Don't get so greedy ❤️" Maybe?
「お宝より魅力的な”モノ”見つけちゃった…？」
"Did you find something 'more appealing' than treasure...?"
いいじゃない❤️)
Isn't that nice? ❤️)
誘うガーネットの赤 極上の海賊の秘宝
The alluring red of garnet, the ultimate pirate's treasure.
それは私
That is me.
艶が溢れ漂う 香りをどうかしらまないで 開けてみて
Overflowing with charm, don't shy away from the scent—try opening it.
(アッハッハッハ…❤️)
(Ah-ha-ha-ha... ❤️)
sexy世界一 superピチピチ
Sexy world number one, super fresh and plump,
ぶっちぎり船長 捕まえたいでしょ？
Uncatchable Captain, don't you want to catch her?
you’re gonna get the treasure
You're gonna get the treasure
maybe tasting me
私の甘さが欲しいでしょ
You want my sweetness, don't you?
(ah-hoy!!da-ba-da-boi)
(Ah-hoy!! Da-ba-da-boi)
秘宝の鍵を
The key to the treasure
(ah-hoy!!da-ba-da-boi)
(Ah-hoy!! Da-ba-da-boi)
優しく刺して
Gently pierce it
(ah-hoy!!da-ba-da-boi)
(Ah-hoy!! Da-ba-da-boi)
宝庫の扉 (あ❤️あ❤️あ！❤️あ！❤️)
The vault door (Ah ❤️ Ah ❤️ Ah! ❤️ Ah! ❤️)
マジで早く開けて (❤️ ahoy ❤️) (❤️ ahoy ❤️)
Open it for real, really fast! (❤️ Ahoy ❤️) (❤️ Ahoy ❤️)
じれったい貴方の手 海図にこぼす甘い溜息のtease
Your impatient hands, a sweet sigh spilled on the chart to tease.
(yeah…)
(Yeah...)
純紅のバラが しおれる前に
Before the crimson rose withers,
we will sail the seven seas
(七つの大海を)
(The seven seas)
summer sun smiling with glee
(股にかけ進め)
(Straddle and advance)
shining ocean of marine
(股ってワードからなになに想像してんの)
(What kind of imagination are you getting from the word "straddle"?)
now please grant my dearest dream
open up this box
open it right now or i will scream
(さもなきゃ)
(Or else)
aaaaaaaaaaaa ! ! ! ! ! ! !
Aaaaaaaaaaaaa! ! ! ! ! ! !
(あけろおおおおおおおお!!)
(Open it up!!)
泣く子も黙る naughty 悩殺ビーム
A naughty, captivating beam that silences even crying children.
キミたちももう我慢できなくなる？ (kaboom…)
Can't you guys control yourselves anymore either? (Kaboom...)
you’re gonna own the pleasure
You're gonna own the pleasure
maybe love of me ?
Maybe love of me?
私の全てを手に入れて (❤️‍🔥❤️‍🔥❤️‍🔥ahhh❤️❤️❤️)
Get all of me (❤️‍🔥❤️‍🔥❤️‍🔥 Ahhh ❤️❤️❤️)
(ah-hoy!!da-ba-da-boi)
(Ah-hoy!! Da-ba-da-boi)
金銀財宝はした金でしょ しわしわになっちゃう 誰か助けて
Gold and silver treasures are small change, I'll get all wrinkled, someone help me!
マジで遠慮しすぎ キミたち何考えてんの 分かってるんだわ欲望
Seriously holding back too much, what are you guys thinking? I know your desires.
だから今すぐ開けてよ 宝箱 貴方を待つガーネット…
So open it right now, treasure chest, the garnet waiting for you...
(キミ…キミたち…開けて～！！)
(You... You guys... Open it up~!!)
魅惑を隠す箱
A box hiding allure,
秘宝に香る危なげな
the dangerous scent of hidden treasure
dangerous marine smell
❤️ ahoy ❤️
(見出そうどこを 探しに来たけど)
(Where did I come looking...)
目移り腕まくり
Wandering eyes, rolling up sleeves...
一緒バケーションの華が 満開展開 幸せ先回り
The flower of vacation together, blooming fully, anticipating happiness.
縦書き秘密を 分け合うヤツに 押され気味ですの
I'm getting overwhelmed by the one sharing vertical secrets.
あいつに出会うと タイミング合うと 攻められ いじられ やめてやめてあはん❤️
Meeting him, timing it right, being teased and picked on—stop, stop, ahn ❤️
こいつ狙われて 振り回されて 雨とムシを使いこなす
Being targeted and pushed around, mastering rain and bugs.
逃げたいくらい いじめられちゃう
I'm being bullied to the point of wanting to run away.
だけど変わったりすなの
But don't change either.
ポツリ ポツリ 泣いたり ホントしたり ひとしきり ワクワク
Crying one by one, being true, getting excited for a while.
きっとずっと 胸がキュンとしちゃう
Surely my chest will keep fluttering.
キュンとキュンとしちゃう花 自分からはいチーズ❤️ ahoy ❤️
A flower that makes my heart flutter—say cheese ❤️ Ahoy ❤️
(ふんふんふんふんふん…)
(Mm-mm-mm-mm-mm...)
(あけろおおおおおおおお!!)
(Open it up!!)
縦書き秘密を 分け合うヤツに 押され気味ですの
I'm getting overwhelmed by the one sharing vertical secrets.
あいつに出会うと タイミング合うと 攻められ いじられ やめてやめて あ、はぁ…❤️
Meeting him, timing it right, being teased and picked on—stop, stop, ah... ❤️
(❤️ ahoy ❤️)
あいつに出会うと タイミング合うと
Meeting him, timing it right,
攻められ いじられ やめてやめて あ、はぁ…❤️
being teased and picked on—stop, stop, ah... ❤️
こいつ狙われて 振り回されて 雨とムシを使いこなす
Being targeted and pushed around, mastering rain and bugs.
逃げたいくらい いじめられちゃう
I'm being bullied to the point of wanting to run away.
だけど変わったりすなの
But don't change either.
ポツリ ポツリ 泣いたり ホントしたり ひとしきり ワクワク
Crying one by one, being true, getting excited for a while.
きっとずっと 胸がキュンとしちゃう
Surely my chest will keep fluttering.
キュンとキュンとしちゃう花 自分からはいチーズ❤️ ahoy ❤️
A flower that makes my heart flutter—say cheese ❤️ Ahoy ❤️
(ふんふんふんふんふん…)
(Mm-mm-mm-mm-mm...)
ポツリ ポツリ 泣いたり ホントしたり ひとしきり ワクワク
Crying one by one, being true, getting excited for a while.
きっとずっと 胸がキュンとしちゃう 華とはい系しょ ❤️ ahoy ❤️
Surely my chest will keep fluttering, what a high-class show ❤️ Ahoy ❤️
はーい！というわけで、メルちゃん！
Hii! So, Mel-chan!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
わーーー！ありがとー！うれしー！やったー！
Waーーー! Thank youー! I'm so happy! Yay!
あ、そうださ、去年の誕生日ライブにもマリン来てくれたよね。
Oh, that's right, Marine came to my birthday live last year too.
そうだよ！メルちゃんさ…
That's right! Mel-chan, like...
え、もしかして、マリンのこと好き？
Eh, could it be, do you like Marine?
え？
Eh?
引いたんじゃねえよ！
Don't look repulsed!
いや、でもまあ、メルね、マリンともっと遊びたいと思ってるよ。
No, but you know, Mel wants to play more with Marine.
お？
Oh?
うん、人間界にも最近来たばかりだしさ。
Yeah, you only recently came to the human world and all.
今度はさ、うちに来ないか？マリン。
Next time, won't you come over to my place, Marine?
え、メルちゃんんちに出張、いったい何されちゃうの？
Eh, going to Mel-chan's house for a business trip, what on earth will be done to me?
え？この前の続きに決まってるでしょ？
Eh? It's obviously the continuation of last time!
なんだっけ、続き、こないだ、こないだだとかちょっと過去すぎて忘れちゃったけど、なんだっけ？
What was it, the continuation, the other day, the other day was a bit too long ago so I forgot, what was it again?
マリをさ、誘っといて、ネタにするんだよ！
You invited Mari, and then made a joke out of it!
誘っ、誘ったのってメルちゃん、じゃあ自意識過剰だな、別に誘ってないんだけど。
Invi— Mel-chan, you invited me, then you're just being self-conscious, I didn't particularly invite you.
誘ったでしょ！ちゃんと来たよ、すぐに！秒で来たじゃん！
You did invite me! I came right away, instantly! You came in seconds!
秒で！
In seconds!
おおー、まあちゃんちょっと、ちょっと忘れてたけど、今度はメルちゃんち…行こうかな。
Ooh, well, I kinda forgot, but next time I guess I'll go to Mel-chan's house...
やったー！決まりね！
Yay! It's settled!
メル、マジでマリンのこと好きだな、困ったな。
Mel really likes Marine, this is troublesome.
うん、はいはいはいはい、じゃあじゃあ。
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, so, so.
ははは、何せ、一周年、に…
Haha, anyway, for the 1st anniversary, tw...
ね、二人で、ね、二人での2ライブだから、なんかポーズ一緒に撮ろう？
Hey, since it's a live for just the two of us, let's take a pose together?
おお、いいよいいよ、で、どのポーズにする？
Oh, sure sure, so, what pose should we do?
そうだの、さっきの局中だと、なんか…
That's right, during the song just now, like...
もしメルで、
If Mel's cute,
もしマリンだとしたら、
then Marine is cute too, right?
あ、確かに。
Ah, true.
ちょっと、うん、逆のほうがいいかな。
Wait, inverse maybe?
あ、マリン攻め？
Ah, Marine'same?
いやちょっとスーパーダーリン見せるか。
Wait, I'll show you Super Darling!
いやでもさ、
Wait, no, wait.
スーパーダーリン！
Super Darling?
いやでもさ、ASMR系？
No, ASMR...
ASMR系の方がいいのかな。
ASMR style would be better, right?
そう、ちょっと精一杯のマリンのいじめを見たいかな。
Right? I want to see a bit of Marine's full-effort teasing.
あー、なるほど。
Ah, I see!
じゃあちょっと、メルちゃん、ちょっと歯を食いしばってもらっても？
Then, Mel, please grit your teeth for a moment!
え、いいかな？
Is that okay?
バシーン！
Punch!
あ！
Ah!
メル！メルこの歌、この歌！
Mel! Mel, this song...
メル、これ好きだな？ひざまずきなさい！ひざまずけ！
Mel, you love it, right? Kneel!
あら、最高！
Oh, so cute!
これだ、これだ、これだ、これ最高でしょ！好きです！
This is it, this is it, this is it!
気持ちいい！
It feels so good!
やっぱツンデレなんだよ、こういう曲気持ちいいのよね。
I love it when it's a tsundere song!
最高！
Too good!
あ、こんな変態とはお友達でいられません！
Ah, crazy people aren't allowed here with friends!
お前も変態だろが！
You're the crazy one!
あ、ちょっとバレちゃったな。
Ah, I messed up.
ちょっと、なんかたれてきちゃった、なんか汚い空気になってきちゃったから。
It's getting messy and filthy.
かわいいポーズをとろっか。
Let's strike a cute pose.
あ、そうだね。じゃあラストはちょっと可愛く決めちゃおうか。
Right, right. The last one should be cute.
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
じゃあさ、一緒にさ、ちょっと二人愛し合ってるってことが完全に判明したから、
So, it's completely clear that we two love each other,
ハート作ろっか。
let's make a heart!
オッケー。ハートね、一緒に。
Okay, a heart together!
二人で一緒に。
Let's do it together.
はい、それでは、はい、せーの！
Alright, then, ready, set!
いぇーい！
Yay!
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world,
そういう扱い心得てよね
make sure you know how to treat me right!
あー……
Ah...
よね！
Yeah!
その一、いつもと違う髪型に気付くこと
Rule one: notice when my hair is different,
その二、ちゃんと靴まで見ること　いいでしょ?
rule two: look closely at my shoes, okay?
その三、わたしたの一言には
Rule three: for every word I say,
三つの言葉で返事すること
reply with three words.
わかったら右手がお留守なの　なんとかして!
If you understand, do something about my neglected right hand!
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything,
キミに心から思ってほしいの　かわいいって
I just want you to think from your heart that I'm cute!
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world,
気が付いて　ねえねえ
notice me, hey, hey!
待たせるなんて論外よ　わたしを誰だと思ってるの?
Making me wait is out of the question, who do you think I am?
もう　なんだか　あまいものが食べたい!
Gosh, I suddenly want to eat something sweet!
欠点?かわいいの間違いでしょ
Flaws? You mean cute, right?
文句は許しませんの
I won't allow any complaints.
あのね?私の話ちゃんと聞いてる?　ちょっと……
Hey, are you listening to me properly? Hellooo...
あ、それとね?　白いお馬さん　決まってるでしょ?
Oh, and also, a white horse, it's obvious, isn't it?
迎えに来て
Come pick me up.
わかったらかしずいて　手を取って“おひめさま”って
If you understand, then kneel, take my hand, and say "princess"!
別のん　わがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything,
でもね　少しぐらい叱ってくれたっていいのよ?
but you know, it's okay if you scold me just a little bit.
世界でわたしだけのおうじさま
The one and only prince in the world just for me,
気が付いて　ほらほら　おててが空いてます
notice me, look, look, my hands are empty!
無口で無愛想なおうじさま
The quiet and aloof prince,
もう　どうして!　気が付いてよ早く
why! Notice me already!
ぜったいキミはわかってない!
Seriously, you just don't get it,
わかってないわ!
you just don't get it at all!
いちごの乗ったショートケーキ
Strawberry shortcake,
こだわり卵のとろけるプリン
みんな　みんな　我慢します
everybody, everybody, command me!
わがままだと思わないでよね
Don't think I'm just being selfish,
私だってやればできるもん　あとで後悔するわよ?
I can do it if I try, I'll regret it later!
当然でしょ?　だってわたしは
Of course, because I am
世界で一番おひめさま
the number one princess in the world,
ちゃんと見ててよね?
you're watching me properly, right?
どこかにいっちゃうよくに　抱きしめられちゃうぞ?
Whenever, wherever, you'll hold me tight, right?
世界で一番おひめさま
I'm the number one princess in the whole wide world,
そういう扱い心得てよね
so make sure you know how to treat me.
その一 いつもと違う髪型に気付くこと
Number one, notice when my hair is styled differently.
その二 ちゃんとする靴まで見ること いいね?
Number two, look down at my shoes, okay?
みんなー！
Everyone!
こんかぷー！ライブ楽しんでるー？
Konkapuu! Are you enjoying the live?
めいぷーとってもね、めちゃくちゃ楽しんでるよ、めるは！
Meippuu, Mel is really, really enjoying it!
今年のハロウィンも誕生日も みんなのおかげでめちゃくちゃ楽しい！ありがとう！
This year's Halloween and birthday are super fun thanks to everyone! Thank you!
でね、今回のステージもう気付いてくれたかなー？
And hey, did you already notice this stage?
今回もね、める仕様に、なんと作っていただけましたー！どどん！
This time too, it was made specially for Mel! Ta-da!
かわいいでしょ？すごいでしょう？
Cute, right? Amazing, right?
ねー、めちゃくちゃかわいい。
Right? Super cute.
今日はね、いつもよりもすごい告知があります！それはこのあと説明するので、ぜひ最後まで聞いてってね！
Today, there's an even bigger announcement than usual! I'll explain it after this, so be sure to listen until the end!
まずは……
First is...
じゃじゃじゃじゃーん！夜空メル誕生日記念グッズ2022！ととととーん！
Ta-da! Yozora Mel Birthday Commemorative Goods 2022! Ta-da!
今回もかわいいグッズをいっぱい用意してます！
We've prepared lots of cute goods this time too!
その1！夜空メルバースデーライト〜LEDアクリルスタンドライト〜になってます！
Number 1! Yozora Mel Birthday Light ~LED Acrylic Stand Light~!
朝木ゆうな先生描き下ろしのイラストだよ！
It's an illustration drawn by Asagi Yuuna-sensei!
かっこいいでしょ？なんか、いつもね、かわいいメルだけど、今回はかっこかわいいメルに描いていただきましたー！
Cool, right? Usually Mel is cute, but this time I was drawn as cool and cute!
お部屋でね、ぜひ使ってください！
Please use it in your room!
そして、その2！魔界の晩餐会グラス！
And number 2! Makai no Bansankai Glass!
これワイングラスです！これね、メルずっと作りたかったんだよねー！
This is a wine glass! I've always wanted to make this!
メルはアースラジュースを入れてね、飲むつもりだけど、みんなはワインとかぶどうジュースとか入れてね、ぜひ、こうやってね、「乾杯！」って言って飲んでください！いっぱい使ってね！
Mel plans to put Ursula juice in and drink, but everyone put wine or grape juice and please drink saying "Cheers!" Use it a lot!
その3！メルの魔導書パスケース！
Number 3! Mel's Grimoire Pass Case!
これはパスケースになってます！日常でぜひいっぱい使ってほしいな！
This is a pass case! I hope you use it a lot in your daily life!
実はね、この本の柄、今後ね、メルの配信や歌ってみたなので、今後出てくる予定があります！
Actually, this book pattern is scheduled to appear in Mel's future streams and cover songs!
何かでは、ちょっと今内緒なんだけど、その時のお楽しみということで、皆さんぜひ先取りでゲットしてほしいな！
For something, it's a secret right now, but as something to look forward to then, I hope you all get it in advance!
そして、次がビッグなお知らせ！その4！じゃじゃじゃーん！夜空メル1stアルバム『Twinkle Star Magic』です！
And next is big news! Number 4! Ta-da! Yozora Mel 1st Album "Twinkle Star Magic"!
これはぜひゲットしてほしい！もう一番ゲットしてほしいやつ！
You definitely want to get this! The one I want you to get the most!
かっこいい曲からね、かわいい曲、しっとり曲などなどいっぱい詰め込みました！
From cool songs to cute songs, emotional songs, etc., packed full!
いろんなメルを知ってほしいなって思って、あの、たくさんね、詰め込んだのでぜひ聴いてほしいです！全部でなんと！
Wanting you to know various sides of Mel, I packed a lot into it, so please listen! In total,なんと!
どどん！11曲あります！
Ta-da! There are 11 songs!
メルね、5ヶ月連続で、あの、オリジナル曲リリースしてたんですけど、『Cpotte Night Sky』からのいままでのオリジナル曲、そしてね、まだ配信されてない曲がなんと5曲も入って、豪華ね、全曲になってます！
Mel released original songs for 5 consecutive months, but from 'Cpotte Night Sky' up to now, plus 5 unreleased songs, making a luxurious full tracklist!
さらにさらに！メルの初めてのオリジナル曲『Cpotte Night Sky』のリミックスバージョンも入っています！
Furthermore! A remix version of Mel's very first original song 'Cpotte Night Sky' is also included!
さらにさらに！デイリーダイアリーの夜空メル歌唱バージョンも入ってます！これをね、メル1人でね、5役演じて歌いました！めちゃ頑張ったから聴いてください！
Furthermore! Yozora Mel's solo vocal version of Daily Diary is included! Mel played and sang 5 roles all by herself! I worked really hard on it so please listen!
お姉さんボイスとか少年ボイスとかね、そんな感じで歌ったので聴いてください！よろしくお願いします！
With sister voice and boy voice, I sang it like that so please listen! Thank you very much!
え、今回ね、グッズ全部買ってくれた人には今回も特典があります！
Um, this time too, for those who bought all the goods, there are special benefits!
1つ目はメルからの書き下ろしお手紙「かぶ民へのラブレター」です！
First is a handwritten letter from Mel "Love Letter to Kabumin"!
これを初めてかも知れないね。
This might be the first time.
その2、えーと、ASMRボイス！こっちもね、甘々になっているので、合わせて、全部合わせてね、
Second, um, ASMR voice! This one is super sweet too, so combine them, combine all of them,
あの、聞いて、見てください！ぜ、ぜ、ぜ、ぜ、びゅー！めちゃ噛んだわ！もう歌いまくってさ、呼吸がいっぱい！ぜひゲットしてください！
Um, listen and watch! Plea... please get it! I stumbled so much! After singing so much, out of breath! Please definitely get it!
ちょっと告知ごち長くなっちゃったけど、今日はこのあとメンバー限定でね、アフターライブ！
The announcement got a bit long, but today after this, for members only, an after live!
アフターライブ！やります！メンバーのみんな
We're doing an after live! Everyone in members...
もっと もっと 一緒に
More, more, together,
もうちょっとだけ 一緒にいたいなと思って
wanting to be together just a little longer,
予定を作ったんだけど メルと一緒にいてくれますか？
I made plans. Will you stay with me, Mel?
やった！ 約束だよ。
Yay! It's a promise.
じゃあ 次が最後の曲になります。
Now, this will be our final song.
きっともうカップ民のみんななら 愛のってね ばっちりだよね？ 大丈夫だよね？
I'm sure all you Kapu-min have the rhythm down pat, right? You'll be fine, right?
知らないよって人がいたら まあこの後ね ダウンロードしてください めっちゃいい曲なので 聞いてほしいです
If anyone doesn't know it, well, please download it afterwards. It's a really great song, so I want you to listen to it.
今日もね 本当に本当に ありがとう カップ民のみんな！
And today, truly, truly, thank you everyone in Kapu-min!
大好きだよ！ カプッ！
I love you so much! Chomp!
年の数より 年の数だけ それは贅沢
More than our age, just the number of our years, that's a luxury.
お菓子をちょーだい
Give me treats!
おばけがかきわけ 夜をかけてゆく
Ghosts push their way through, running through the night.
わたし ヴァンパイア あなたの
I'm a vampire, of you...
か ぷ い ん あ
Kapuiin, ah!
ぱっぱらパンプキンが覗いて てってれ照れちゃって
Pa-para pumpkin is peeking, feeling so shy and embarrassed.
ジャック・オー・ランタンくんも 私からドキドキしてるの
Even Jack-o'-Lantern-kun is getting nervous because of me.
もっと近くが 好き
I love being even closer.
近づいて パックすりお
Getting closer...
かぷいん お・は・ろ・は・ろ・うぃん-うぃん かぶってしたら
Kapuiin, Oh-Hallo-Halloween, if you put it on,
お・は・ろ・は・ろ・うぃん-うぃん るんるんるん
Oh-Hallo-Halloween, run-run-run,
お・は・ろ・は・ろ・うぃん-うぃん そんなカンケイ
Oh-Hallo-Halloween, that kind of relationship,
かぷいん かぷいん かぷいん かぷいん かぷいん かぷいん With you
Kapuiin, kapuiin, kapuiin, kapuiin, kapuiin, kapuiin With you!
魔女 悪魔 フランケン ゾンビ ミイラ
Witch, devil, Frankenstein, zombie, mummy,
逢魔が時の大目玉ぞろい
a lineup of the biggest monsters of the gloaming.
おーるでい 首づけの首づけ
All day long, attaching our necks,
ワクワクしてるよ いざParty Night
We're excited, now for Party Night!
おみみに かぷかぷ おなかに たぷたぷ
Nibbling at ears, stuffing our bellies,
新たに せーぶん たくさんちょーだい
Give me lots of fresh vitality!
月明かり かぎ分け 夜をかけてゆく
Pushing aside the moonlight, running through the night,
わたし ヴァンパイア
I'm a vampire.
かぷいん お・は・ろ・は・ろ・うぃん-うぃん かぶってしたら
Kapuiin, Oh-Hallo-Halloween, if you put it on,
お・は・ろ・は・ろ・うぃん-うぃん るんるんるん
Oh-Hallo-Halloween, run-run-run,
お・は・ろ・は・ろ・うぃん-うぃん そんなカンケイ
Oh-Hallo-Halloween, that kind of relationship,
かぷいん かぷいん かぷいん かぷいん かぷいん かぷいん With you
Kapuiin, kapuiin, kapuiin, kapuiin, kapuiin, kapuiin With you!
キュートが過ぎちゃって ごめんね！
I'm too cute, sorry!
ボン・キュッ・ボンで セクシーポーズ
Sexy pose with a bon-kyu-bon figure!
あなたのココロとカラダに メル！ メル！
Mel! Mel! right into your heart and body!
魔界の？ 最強！ かわいい！ ヴァンパイアって～？
The demon world's? Strongest! Cutest! Vampire～?
夜空メル！
Yozora Mel!
ぱっぱらパンプキンはどこにいる
Where is the pa-para pumpkin?
とっとこ遠くまで行こうよ
Let's go far away, clip-clop.
ジャック・オー・ランタンくんの浮気者
Jack-o'-Lantern-kun, you flirt.
ボコボコにしても連れて帰る覚悟して
Even if I beat you up, I'm taking you home, so be prepared.
かぷいん 離れたくないよ 離さないよ
Kapuiin, I don't want to be apart, I won't let go.
いつまでもずっと 一緒がいいな
I want us to be together forever.
このお祭り 共に過ごそう
Let's spend this festival together.
かぷいん お・は・ろ・は・ろ・うぃん-うぃん かぶってしたら
Kapuiin, Oh-Hallo-Halloween, if you put it on,
お・は・ろ・は・ろ・うぃん-うぃん るんるんるん
Oh-Hallo-Halloween, run-run-run,
お・は・ろ・は・ろ・うぃん-うぃん そんなカンケイ
Oh-Hallo-Halloween, that kind of relationship,
かぷいん かぷいん かぷいん かぷいん かぷいん かぷいん With you かぷいん中毒
Kapuiin, kapuiin, kapuiin, kapuiin, kapuiin, kapuiin With you (Kapuiin addiction)!